Adalberto Acosta

A.Acosta@IEEE.org (206) 304-9544

Available: December 12th, 2024

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/adalberto-acosta Portfolio: https://adalbertoacosta.github.io

Expected Graduation: December 2024

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages—C++, Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML

Software—MS Teams, GitHub, VS Code, Docker, Atlassian Suite

GENERAL SKILLS

Communication—Fluent in Spanish and English; efficient use of team communication software (e.g., Slack, Microsoft Teams, etc.).

Teamwork—Excited to problem solve with others, Outgoing, Adaptable, Passion for innovating fueled by peers, Excels in a fast-paced environment. Experience using the agile scrum software development methodology.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Seattle Pacific University, Seattle, WA

- Led a team of 5 as Scrum Master using the agile Scrum software development methodology for one school year.
- Coursework in data structures, algorithms, and general development of software applications.

Associate of Arts June 2022

Highline College, Des Moines, WA

GPA: 3.52

• Worked in a diverse team to develop a Java application involving data structures, user input, and a graphical interface.

EXPERIENCE

Graduation Planning App

Seattle, WA

September 2023 - Present

- Built a full-stack application for students and advisors at Seattle Pacific University to assist over 2,000 students in planning out 4 years of courses.
- Led a team of 5 computer science students as a Scrum Master for an entire school year, with 13 completed Sprints and over 100 completed issues.

Landscaping/Construction

Seattle, WA

January 2018 - Present

- Working in a team to problem-solve and meet customer expectations related to fencing, retaining walls, and general yard maintenance.
- 6 years of experience satisfying client needs and developing more cost-effective solutions.

Hackathon 2022 October 2022

Seattle, WA

- Worked in a team to create a dynamic menu for customers and restaurant owners with a time limit of 28 hours.
- Considered customer and administrative needs then designed a plan for the web application.
- Created front end using HTML/CSS and the ASP.NET framework.

Data Verification Volunteer

February 2022 - March 2022

Hunger-Free America, Worked Remotely

- Reached out to over 50 food banks and verified pre-existing databases of information.
- Improved and updated information available to those in need of food resources.

Phone Banking to Increase Food Access

February 2022 - March 2022

Hunger Free America, Worked Remotely

- Worked with a team and called more than 500 seniors who requested information on government programs for food access.
- Deliberated and shared ideas to optimize interactions with seniors and increase overall outreach.